Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives: Miscellaneous Periodicals Collection ALBA.282
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives: Miscellaneous Periodicals Collection
Bulk, 1937-1939
1924-2011
ALBA.282
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
8.25 linear feet (17 boxes)
This is an open collection of miscellaneous periodicals that relate closely to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at New York University; magazines and newspapers in the collection were published in Spain and abroad during the Spanish Civil War and in later years. Although the provenance of many items is unknown, it is clear that some were separated from manuscript collections that form part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at the Tamiment Library, NYU; others may have been brought from Spain as souvenirs by Lincoln Brigade members; and some purchased from dealers or given to archives over the years by collectors and others. While some were produced in Spain during the war years and relate directly to the conflict, others may contain only an article or articles on the War and reactions to it around the world. Individual publications in the collection were produced by many publishers and political entities, including a wide array of political and trade-union organizations. The contents of the collection may change over time, as new donations are made. Individual items in the collection have not been catalogued into the main on-line catalogue of New York University. Publications have been set aside for inclusion in this collection for a variety of reasons. Many titles are represented by only one issue; others are in such fragile condition that they may be handled only under the supervision of archives staff; in some cases the items in this collection are duplicate issues of titles that can be found in longer runs in the Library catalogue. To be sure of locating the full range of Spanish Civil War-related periodicals available at the Tamiment Library, researchers should consult both this collection and the main on-line catalogue of Bobst Library, NYU.
Tamiment Library.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
This is an open collection of miscellaneous periodicals that relate closely to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at New York University but have not been catalogued into the main on-line catalogue of the University. Publications have been set aside for inclusion in this collection for a variety of reasons. Many titles are represented by only one issue; others are in such fragile condition that they may be handled only under the supervision of archives staff; in some cases the items in this collection are duplicate issues of titles that can be found in longer runs in the Library catalogue. To be sure of locating the full range of Spanish Civil War-related periodicals available at the Tamiment Library, researchers should consult both this collection and the main on-line catalogue of Bobst Library, NYU.
Historical/Biographical Note
The collection consists of a wide range of periodicals published in Spain and abroad during the Spanish Civil War and in later years. Although the provenance of many items is unknown, it is clear that some were separated from manuscript collections that form part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at the Tamiment Library, NYU; others may have been brought from Spain as souvenirs by Lincoln Brigade members; and some purchased from dealers or given to archives over the years by collectors and others. While some were produced in Spain during the war years and relate directly to the conflict, others may contain only an article or articles on the War and reactions to it around the world. Individual publications were produced by many publishers and political entities, including an array of political and trade-union organizations. The contents of this collection may change over time, as new donations are made.
Provenance
The bulk of the collection came to the Tamiment Library, NYU as part of the original accession of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) material transferred from Brandeis University in 2001. Some items have been added since, and the collection remains open for additions.
Periodicals.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Periodicals.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Sources.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Foreign public opinion.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x International brigades.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, Foreign.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Refugees.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.; Spain |x Politics and government |y 1939-1975 |v Periodicals.; Spain.
- ABC (Madrid: Diario Republican de Izquierdas) (Box 1)
  - Number Extraordinario/Year Trigesimo (Supplemento Grafico de Actualidades y Year Trigesimo, Number 9.792 -- Edicion de la manana), 12 Oct 1934 (Box 1)
  - Year XXXIII, Number 10.686, 11 Aug 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year XXXVIII, Number 43 (Organo de Union Republicana), 29 Aug 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year XXXVIII, Number 43 and Edicion de la manana, 29 May 1937 (Box 1)
- Accion Republicana (Mexico: Organo de Izquierda Republicana) (Box 1)
  - Year VIII, Number 61, 14 Feb 1938 (Box 1)
- Acero (Spain: Organo del 5th Cuerpo de Ejercito) (Box 9)
  - Year I, Number 2, Nov 1937 (Box 9)
  - Number 8, Segunda Epoca: Frente del Ebro, 16 Oct 1938 (Box 9)
- Ahora -- Diario de la Juventud (Madrid) [fragile / consult staff] (Box 1)
  - Year VIII, 2 epoca, Number 150, 19 Jun 1937 (Box 1)
  - Number 220, 7 Sep 1937 (Box 1)
- Amanecer (Barcelona: CNT-FAI, Organo de la Escuela de Militantes de Cataluna) (Box 9)
  - Year II, Number 6, Apr 1937 (Box 9)
- America: A Catholic Review of the Week (New York) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 9)
  - Volume LVIII, Number 3, 23 Oct 1937 (Box 9)
- American Socialist Monthly (New York: Socialist Party of the U.S.A.) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 9)
  - Volume 5, Number 5, Jul 1936 (Box 9)
  - Volume 5, Number 8, Dec 1936 (Box 9)
  - Volume 5, Number 9, Feb 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume 6, Number 1, May 1937 (Box 9)
- El Amigo del Pueblo: Portavoz de los amigos de Durruti (Barcelona) (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 2, 26 May 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 3, 12 Jun 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 5, 20 Jul 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 9, 20 Oct 1937 (Box 1)
  - 3er, Pasquin, Sep 1961 (Box 1)
- Among Friends (New York: Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 1 (x2), Winter 1938 (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 2 (x2), Spring 1938 (Box 9)
- Analectos (Montevideo) (Box 9)
  - Year I, Number 3/4, Nov/Dec 1937 (Box 9)
- Ariel: Revista de Hechos e Ideas (Los Angeles) (Box 9)
  - Year I, Number 3, Nov 1939 (Box 9)
- El Artillero de la Libertad (Valencia: Base de Artilleria de las Brigadas Internacionales) (Box 9)
  - Year I, Number 1, Jan 1938 (Box 9)
- Avance: Organo de Opinion Socialista [Spain?] (Box 9)
  - New Series, Number 4, Oct - Nov 1966 (Box 9)
- Avancada [Catalunya?: POUM] (Box 9)
  - Year I, Number 5, 21 Nov 1936 (Box 9)
- Avanti! (Milan, Paris: Partito Socialista Italiano) -- [fragile / consult staff] [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 1)
  - Year XLII, Number 10 (2nd series), Jun 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year XLII, Number 28 (New Series, Year IV, Number 28), 10 Jul 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year XLII, Number 21 (2nd Series), 1 Dec 1937 (Box 1)
- Avanzada (Albacete: Semanario Comunista del Comite Provincial de Albacete) [fragile / consult staff] (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 8, 14 Sep 1937 (Box 1)
- Aviazione Legionaria (Rome: Editoriale Aeronautica) (Box 1)
  - Year XVI, 1937 (Box 1)
- Ayuda (Madrid: Semanario de la Solidaridad) (Box 1)
  - Year II, Number 69, 22 Mar 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year II, Number 71, 4 Sep 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year II, Number 73 (x3), 18 Sep 1937 (Box 1)
- Ayuda - Tribuna de la Solidaridad (Mexico) (Box 9)
  - Number 116, Epoca II, 10 Feb 1940 (Box 9)
- Ayuda Medica Internacional (Barcelona: Periodico de la Ayuda Medica Extranjera) (Box 9)
  - Number 9 (x2), 1 Feb 1938 (Box 9)
  - Number 10, 1 Mar 1938 (Box 9)
- La Batalla (Barcelona: Organo del Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista) (Box 1)
  - Year VII, Number 260, 17 Jul 1936 (Box 1)
  - II Epoca - Number 238, 9 May 1937 (Box 1)
  - Epoca III, Number 1 (First Illegal Issue), 10 Jul 1937 (Box 1)
  - Epoca III, Number 3, 5 Aug 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 4, 14 Aug 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 5, 21 Aug 1937 (Box 1)
- La Batalla Obrera (Barcelona: Organo Central del Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista) (Box 1)
  - Epoca I - Number 2, 18 Mar 1937 (Box 1)
- Beehive Review (Brooklyn: Young Communist League) [fragile: Use photocopies in same box] (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 1, May 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 2, Jun 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 3, Aug 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 4, Oct 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 5, Nov 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume I, Number 6, Dec 1937 (Box 9)
  - Volume II, Number 1, Feb 1938 (Box 9)
  - Volume II, Number 2, May 1938 (Box 9)
  - Volume II, Number 3, Jun 1938 (Box 9)
  - Volume II, Number 4, Sep 1938 (Box 9)
  - Volume IV, Number 1 (Cover), Undated (Box 9)
  - Volume IV, Number 2 (Cover), Undated (Box 9)
- Blanco y Negro (Madrid) (Box 9)
  - Year LXXVI, Number 2828, 16 Jul 1966 (Box 9)
- Boletin de Informacion de las Brigadas Internacionales del Ejercito Popular Espanol [Spain?] [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 9)
  - Vol XXX, Number 299, 11 Apr 1937 (Box 9)
- Boletin de Informacion Sindical (Mexico: Union General de Trabajadores de Espana) (Box 9)
  - Year I, Number 6, 1 Oct 1940 (Box 9)
- Boletin Interior (Barcelona: POUM) (Box 9)
  - Number 1, 23 Apr 1937 (Box 9)
  - Number 2, 29 May 1937 (Box 9)
- Boletin Interior (Madrid: POUM, Seccion de Madrid) (Box 9)
  - Number IV, Apr 1937 (Box 9)
- Botwin (partial issue), Undated (Box 12)
  - Botwin (Partial Issue -- in Yiddish), Undated (Box 12)
- Call of Youth (New York: National Executive Committee of the Workmen's Circle) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 8)
  - Volume V, Number 1, Jan 1937 (Box 8)
- Canto a la Marina (Madrid) (Box 8)
  - Letra de Luis de Tapia Musica de Bacarisse Canciones, "Altavoz del Frente", Undated (Box 8)
- Carteles (Havana) (Box 1)
  - Volume XXIX, Number 29, 18 Jul 1937 (Box 1)
- Castilla Libre ([Madrid?:] CNT-AIT, Confederacion Regional del Trabajo del Centro) (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 248, 20 Nov 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 249, 21 Nov 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 250, 23 Nov 1937 (Box 1)
- Catalunya (Barcelona: Organ Regional de la Confederacion Nacional del Treball) (Box 1)
  - Year I, Epoca I, Number I, 22 Feb 1937 (Box 1)
- Cenit: Sociologia Ciencia Literatura (Toulouse) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 8)
  - Year XXI, Number 200, Oct-Nov-Dec 1971 (Box 8)
- Christian Science Monitor (Boston) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 1)
  - Weekly Magazine Section, 2 Feb 1938 (Box 1)
  - Book Reviews, 11 Jan 1939 (Box 1)
- Claridad (Madrid: UGT) (Box 8)
  - Year II, Number 494, 16 Oct 1937 (Box 8)
- Class Struggle (Chicago: Communist League of Struggle) (Box 8)
  - Volume 6, Number 5, Sep 1936 (Box 8)
  - Volume VII, Number 6-9, Sep 1937 (Box 8)
- Combat (Lleida: Joventut Comunista Iberica, POUM) (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 103, 24 Nov 1936 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 107, 28 Nov 1936 (Box 1)
- El Combate Sindicalista (Valencia: Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo) (Box 1)
  - Year IV, Number 41, 12 Jun 1936 (Box 1)
- Le Combat Syndicaliste (Paris: CNT) [See also NYU Library Catalogue] (Box 1)
  - [Number ?] pp. 5-8, [1971?] (Box 1)
- El Comunista (Valencia: Federacion Levantina del Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista) (Box 1)
  - Year II, Number 27, 13 Feb 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year II, Number 30, 6 Mar 1937 (Box 1)
- Correo de Asturias (Buenos Aires) (Box 1)
  - Year VII, Number 348, 21 Oct 1939 (Box 1)
- El Correo Catalan (Barcelona) (Box 1)
  - Year LXIV, Number 19.752, 31 Mar 1939 (Box 1)
- La Correspondencia Internacional [Paris] (Box 8)
  - Number dedicado a Espana, pp. 25-78, Undated (Box 8)
- Crisol (Madrid) (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 4, 11 Apr 1931 (Box 1)
  - INCOMPLETE pp. 3-10, 9 May 1931 (Box 1)
- Criticon (Barcelona: CNT) (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 13, 14 Aug 1937 (Box 1)
- Cronica (Madrid: Brigatas Internacionales) (Box 1)
  - Year IX, Number 400, 11 Jul 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year IX, Number 417, 7 Nov 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year IX, Number 418, 14 Nov 1937 (Box 1)
  - Unknown Edition (16 pgs.), Undated (Box 1)
- Cultura Proletaria (New York) (Box 1)
  - Year XIII, Number 615, 10 Feb 1940 (Box 1)
  - Year XVI, Number 793, 10 Jul 1943 (Box 1)
- Daily Record (Chicago) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 26 Jan 1939 (Box 1)
  - Volume I, Number 290, 26 Jan 1939 (Box 1)
- Daily Worker (New York) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 28 Mar 1938-23 Jun 1941 (Box 1)
  - Volume XV, Number 74, INCOMPLETE, p.1-2, 28 Mar 1938 (Box 1)
  - Volume XV, Number 97, 22 Apr 1938 (Box 1)
  - Volume XV, Number 109, 6 May 1938 (Box 1)
  - Volume XV, Number 123, 23 May 1938 (Box 1)
- Defensa Nacional (Madrid: Teconica Militia), Aug 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 2, Aug 1937 (Box 1)
- Democracia Espanola (Manila, Philippines: Organo de las Izquierdas Espanolas de Filipinas), Nov 1937 (Box 8)
  - Year I, Number XX, 10 Nov 1937 (Box 8)
- El Dia Grafico (Barcelona: Diario Republicano), 8 Aug 1936 (Box 1)
  - Year XXIV, Number 6.188, 8 Aug 1936 (Box 1)
- El Diluvio (Barcelona: Diario Republicano Democratico Federal), 10 Feb 1938 - 13 Feb 1938 (Box 1)
  - Year LXXXI, Number 35, 10 Feb 1938 (Box 1)
  - Year LXXXI, Number 38, 13 Feb 1938 (Box 1)
- Ejercito del Ebro (Madrid), ca. 1938 (Box 3)
  - Ejercito del Ebro -- inside content (x2), Nov 1938 (Box 3)
  - Number 3 - 1st page / cover (x4), Undated (Box 3)
- Ejercito del Ebro: Encapsulated Issue (Box 3)
  - [Unidentified Issue], circa 1937-1939 (Box 3)
- Ejercito Popular (Barcelona), 28 Apr 1938 (Box 3)
  - Number 1, 28 Apr 1938 (Box 3)
- Ejercito del Pueblo (Barcelona: Partido Comunista de Espana), Sep 1937 (Box 8)
  - Number 8, 3 Sep 1937 (Box 8)
  - Number 9, 17 Sep 1937 (Box 8)
- El Empecinado (Valencia), 27 Aug 1938 (Box 3)
  - Year I, Number 5, 27 Aug 1938 (Box 3)
- L'Espagne Envahie (Paris), Aug 1937 (Box 3)
  - Publication Trimestrielle (x2), Aug 1937 (Box 3)
- Espana (Buenos Aires: Prensa Hispanica), 1937 (Box 8)
  - Number 1, 1937 (Box 8)
- Espana Popular (Mexico), 1959, 1965, 1967, & 1968 (Box 3)
  - Year XIX, Number 886, 15 Sep 1959 (Box 3)
  - Year XXVI, Number 960, Segunda epoca, 30 Sep 1965 (Box 3)
  - Year XXVII, Number 980, Segunda epoca, 15 Dec 1967 (Box 3)
  - Year XXVII, Number 984, Segunda epoca, 15 Aug 1968 (Box 3)
- Espoir (Paris?: AIT, CNT, VI Union Regionale de la CNTF), 1965-1966, 1968, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Number 181, 20 Jun 1965 (Box 3)
  - Number 252, 30 Oct 1966 (Box 3)
  - Number 356, 10 Nov 1968 (Box 3)
  - Number 417, 18 Jan 1970 (Box 3)
- L'Espurna (Girona: POUM a les Comarques Gironines), 20 Nov - 23 Nov 1936 (Box 3)
  - Year I, Number 5, 2nd Epoca, 20 Nov 1936 (Box 3)
  - Year I, Number 7, 2nd Epoca, 23 Nov 1936 (Box 3)
- Estampa (Madrid), 25 Sep 1937 (Box 4)
  - Year X, Number 164, May 1937 (Box 4)
- Estudios (Valencia), May 1937 (Box 8)
  - Year XV, Number 164, May 1937 (Box 8)
- Exelsior (Havana), 26 Jul 1951 (Box 2)
  - Year XXIX, Number 178, 26 Jul 1951 (Box 2)
- The Fight against War and Fascism (New York: American League against War and Fascism) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], Jun 1936 - Aug 1937 (Box 4)
  - Volume 3, [Number 8?] (pp. 1-2 & 29-32 & Advertisement), Jun 1936 (Box 4)
  - Volume 3, Number 9 (w/o cover), Jul 1936 (Box 4)
  - Volume 3, Number 10, Aug 1936 (Box 4)
  - Volume 3, Number 11 (x2), Sep 1936 (Box 4)
  - Volume 4, Number 3, Jan 1937 (Box 4)
  - Volume 4, Number 7 (x2 - Second copy missing cover), May 1937 (Box 4)
  - Volume 4, Number 8 (pp. 4-6), Jun 1937 (Box 4)
  - Volume 4, Number 10 (x2 - 1st Copy missing pp. 31-32 & 2nd Copy Section 1 & 2), Aug 1937 (Box 4)
- The Fight for Peace and Democracy (New York: National Executive Committee of the American League against War and Fascism) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], Jan 1938 - Nov 1938 (Box 4)
  - Volume 5, Number 3, Jan 1938 (Box 4)
  - Volume 5, Number 6 (x3 - 2nd Copy missing pp. 1-4 & 61-64, 3rd Copy missing pp. 63-64), Apr 1938 (Box 4)
  - Volume 5, Number 10 (x2 - 2nd Copy missing pp. 31-32), Aug 1938 (Box 4)
  - Volume 6, Number 1, Nov 1938 (Box 4)
- Fortune (New York: Time) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], Mar 1945 (Box 4)
  - Volume XXXI, Number 3, Mar 1945 (Box 4)
- Free Spain: Bulletin of Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee (New York: Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 1951 - 1955 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 2, 28 Feb 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 3, 23 Mar 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 4, 9 Apr 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 6, 8 May 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 7, 28 May 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 8, 25 Jun 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 9, 3 Aug 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XII, Number 10, 4 Sep 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XIII, Number 1 (x2), 28 Sep 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XIII, Number 2, 22 Oct 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XIII, Number 3, 9 Nov 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XIII, Number 4, 29 Nov 1951 (Box 8)
  - Volume XIII, Number 5, 23 Apr 1951 (Box 8)
  - Number 5, 7 Jan 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 6, 8 Feb 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 7, 12 Mar 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 8, 7 Apr 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 10, 20 May 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 11, 23 Jun 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 12, 21 Aug 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 13, Oct 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 14, Nov 1952 (Box 8)
  - Number 15, Dec 1952 (Box 8)
  - Volume X, Number 2, Feb 1953 (Box 8)
- Frente Estudiantil (Barcelona: Comision Nacional de Movilizacion, Zona Catalana), Oct 1938 (Box 8)
  - Year I, Number 6, 1 Oct 1938 (Box 8)
- Frente Libertario (Madrid: Editado por el comite de defensa), 2 Jan 1937 (Box 4)
  - Number 47, 2 Jan 1937 (Box 4)
- Frente Popular Antifascista (Barcelona: Partido Socialista Unificado de Cataluna), Undated (Box 8)
  - [Unidentified Issue], Undated (Box 8)
- Frente Rojo (Valencia), Oct 1937 (Box 4)
  - Year I, Number 223, 7 Oct 1937 (Box 4)
  - Year I, Number 225, 9 Oct 1937 (Box 4)
  - Year I, Number 226, 11 Oct 1937 (Box 4)
  - Year I, Number 228, 13 Oct 1937 (Box 4)
  - Year I, Number 229, 14 Oct 1937 (Box 4)
- Frente Rojo (Barcelona: Partido Comunista (SEIC)), Oct - Dec 1938 (Box 4)
  - Year II, Number 547, 29 Oct 1938 (Box 4)
  - Year II, Number 554, 6 Nov 1938 (Box 4)
  - Year II, Number 590, 18 Dec 1938 (Box 4)
- Frente Universitario (Valencia: Juventud Estudiantil, UFEH), 1937 (Box 6)
  - Number 11, 24 Jul 1937 (Box 6)
- Frente y Retaguardia (Barcelona and Moscow: Periodico Anarquista), Dec 1937 (Box 6)
  - Number 9/10, Dec 1937 (Box 6)
- Front (Terrassa: Partit Obver d'Unificacio Marxista), 1936 (Box 6)
  - Year I, Number 84, 25 Nov 1936 (Box 6)
- Gaceta Hispana (Sao Paolo, Brazil: Organo de Vinculacion Hispano-Brasilena), 1938 (Box 6)
  - Year III, Number 129, 24 Dec 1938 (Box 6)
- Il Garibaldino (Madrid: Brigata Garibaldi), Oct 1937 (Box 8)
  - Number 15 (x4), 6 Oct 1937 (Box 8)
- Guerra Aerea (Rome: Editorial Aeronautica), Undated (Box 6)
  - Year XVI EF, Undated (Box 6)
- Heraldo de Madrid (Madrid), 1931 (Box 6)
  - Year XLI, Number 14.127 - Edicion de la Noche, 13 May 1931 (Box 6)
  - Year XLI, Number 14.129 - Edicion de la Noche, 15 May 1931 (Box 6)
  - Year XLI, Number 14.168 - Edicion de la Noche, 30 Jun 1931 (Box 6)
- L'Hora (Barcelona: POUM), Feb 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 5, II epoca, 19 Feb 1937 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 5, III epoca, 26 Feb 1937 (Box 1)
- L'Humanite (Paris: Organe Central du Parti Comuniste Francais (SFIC)) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 1937 & 1939 (Box 2)
  - Year 34, Number 14.015, 2 May 1937 (Box 2)
  - Year 36, Number 14.672, 21 Feb 1939 (Box 2)
- L'Illustration (Paris: J.J. Dubochet) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 1936 - 1938 (Box 6)
  - Year 94, Number 4884, 10 Oct 1936 (Box 6)
  - Year 94, Number 4887, 31 Oct 1936 (Box 6)
  - Year 94, Number 4890, 21 Nov 1936 (Box 6)
  - (Guerre Civile en Espagne - deuxieme album hors-serie edite par L'Illustration), Jan 1937 (Box 6)
  - Year 96, Number 4981, 20 Aug 1938 (Box 6)
- Independencia [Spain?], [1938?] (Box 8)
  - XV Cuerpo de Ejercito - Ejercito del Ebro, [1938?] (Box 8)
- Informaciones (Madrid), 22 Apr 1940 (Box 6)
  - Year XV, Number 4.799, 22 Apr 1940 (Box 6)
- Internacional (Velázquez and Madrid: Comite Provincial del SRI de las Brigadas Internacionales), Oct 1937 (Box 7)
  - Number 1, Oct 1937 (Box 7)
- International Review (New York) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], Jan 1936 - Aug 1937 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 1, 15 Jan 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 2, Mar 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 3, Apr 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 4, May 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 5, Jun 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 8, Nov 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 1, Number 9, Dec 1936 (Box 7)
  - Volume 2, Number 1, Jan 1937 (Box 7)
  - Volume 2, Number 2, Feb 1937 (Box 7)
  - Volume 2, Number 3, Apr 1937 (Box 7)
  - Volume 2, Number 5, Jun 1937 (Box 7)
  - Volume 2, Number 6, Aug 1937 (Box 7)
- Italia Libre (San Salvador: Organo Oficial de la Delegacion del Comite Nacional Italia Libre para Centro America), Oct 1942 (Box 7)
  - Year II, Number 18, 29 Oct 1942 (Box 7)
- Izquierda (Jativa: Organo del Partido Izquierda Republicana), 1936 (Box 6)
  - Year II, Number 50, 21 Mar 1936 (Box 6)
- The Jewish Hospital Staff (Brooklyn: Jewish Hospital Branch of the Communist Party), Jul 1938 (Box 7)
  - Volume I, Number 2, Jul 1938 (Box 7)
- Judische Revue (France: Nekudah-Verlag Nukacevo, C.S.R.), May 1937 (Box 7)
  - Volume II, Number 4, May 1937 (Box 7)
- Juventud Espanola (Spain: Spanish Youth Periodical - Hogar Espanol), 1941 (Box 7)
  - 2nd epoca, Number 9, 31 Dec 1941 (Box 7)
- Juventud Obrera (Barcelona: Juventud Comunista Iberica POUM) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 1937 (Box 6)
  - Year I, Number 6, 4th Week of Aug 1937 (Box 6)
- Ken (Chicago), 1938 (Box 6)
  - Volume 1, Number 2, 21 Apr 1938 (Box 6)
- El Liberal [Murcia?], 1937 (Box 6)
  - Year XXXVI, Number 11.610, 29 Sep 1937 (Box 6)
- Liberion (Paris: El Comite de Relaciones), 1924 (Box 1)
  - Year I, Number 5, 5 Mar 1924 (Box 1)
- La Libertad (Madrid: Boletin Interior de las Asociacion de Ex-Presos y Represaliados Politicos (Resistentes Antifascistas)), 1937, 1979, & 1986 (Box 1)
  - Year XIX, Number 5.405, 15 Jul 1937 (Box 1)
  - Number 14, Jun 1979 (Box 1)
  - Number 33, 3er trimester -- Jul - Aug - Sep 1986 (Box 1)
- Libertad Para Espana (Brussels), 15 Nov 1965 (Box 6)
  - [Unidentified Issue], 15 Nov 1965 (Box 6)
- Life (Chicago) [See also NYU Library Catalogue], 1938 & 1961 (Box 6)
  - Volume 4, Number 13, 28 Mar 1938 (Box 6)
  - Volume 31, Number 13, 18 Dec 1961 (Box 6)
- Luz y Fuerza (Barcelona: Portavoz de la Confederación Nacional del Trabajo / Organo de la Federacion Nacional de las Industrias de Agua, Gas y Electricidad), 1937 (Box 7)
  - Epoca Revolucionaria, Number 8, Jul 1937 (Box 7)
  - Epoca Revolucionaria, Number 9, Aug 1937 (Box 7)
- [Mandos: Voluntarios de la Libertad?], Undated (Box 7)
  - (No cover) - pp. 3 -34, Undated (Box 7)
- Medical Relief Bulletin (New York: Medical Bureau, American Friends of Spanish Democracy), 1937 (Box 7)
  - Number 101 (x4), 1 Feb 1937 (Box 7)
  - Number 204 (x2), Jul 1937 (Box 7)
  - Special Issue, Undated (Box 7)
- El Mercantil Valenciano (Valencia: Diario Republicano de Izquierdas), 1939 (Box 6)
  - Year LXVIII, Number 24.358, 11 Jan 1939 (Box 6)
- Meridia (Barcelona: Tribuna del Front Intellectual Antifexista), 1938 (Box 6)
  - Year I, Number 42, 28 Oct 1938 (Box 6)
- Mexico Today (Mexico), 1939 (Box 6)
  - Volume I, Number 3, 28 Jan 1939 (Box 6)